const questions = [
            {
                        question: "What is one of the main benefits of using prescriptive analytics in healthcare?",
                        optionA: "Recommending specific actions to achieve desired outcomes",
                        optionB: "Summarizing historical data",
                        optionC: "Identifying the causes of problems",
                        optionD: "Forecasting future trends",
                        correctOption: "optionA"
                    },
                    {
                        question: "Which type of data challenge involves inconsistencies from different systems?",
                        optionA: "Data Quality and Standardization",
                        optionB: "Data Volume and Complexity",
                        optionC: "Data Privacy and Security",
                        optionD: "Lack of Skilled Workforce",
                        correctOption: "optionA"
                    },
        
                    
                        {
                            question: "What is a key goal of enhancing operational efficiency in healthcare?",
                            optionA: "Increasing the number of patients",
                            optionB: "Expanding the number of facilities",
                            optionC: "Reducing costs and optimizing resource allocation",
                            optionD: "Developing new treatments",
                            correctOption: "optionC"
                        },
                        {
                            question: "Which type of analytics identifies the root causes of problems in healthcare?",
                            optionA: "Descriptive Analytics",
                            optionB: "Diagnostic Analytics",
                            optionC: "Predictive Analytics",
                            optionD: "Prescriptive Analytics",
                            correctOption: "optionB"
                        },
                        {
                            question: "What is the primary focus of predictive analytics in healthcare?",
                            optionA: "Summarizing past events",
                            optionB: "Recommending specific actions",
                            optionC: "Forecasting future trends and outcomes",
                            optionD: "Analyzing reasons behind outcomes",
                            correctOption: "optionC"
                        },
                        {
                            question: "Which type of biomedical signal is generated by mechanical vibrations?",
                            optionA: "Bioelectric Signals",
                            optionB: "Biomechanical Signals",
                            optionC: "Bioacoustic Signals",
                            optionD: "Biomagnetic Signals",
                            correctOption: "optionC"
                        },
                        {
                            question: "What challenge is associated with integrating data from various sources in healthcare?",
                            optionA: "High data accuracy",
                            optionB: "Easy data sharing",
                            optionC: "Massive data volume and complexity",
                            optionD: "Simple data formats",
                            correctOption: "optionC"
                        },
                        {
                            question: "Which analytics technique recommends specific actions to improve outcomes?",
                            optionA: "Descriptive Analytics",
                            optionB: "Diagnostic Analytics",
                            optionC: "Predictive Analytics",
                            optionD: "Prescriptive Analytics",
                            correctOption: "optionD"
                        },
                        {
                            question: "What is a significant challenge related to data privacy in healthcare?",
                            optionA: "High data storage costs",
                            optionB: "Inconsistent data formats",
                            optionC: "Protecting patient privacy while sharing data",
                            optionD: "Overuse of data analytics",
                            correctOption: "optionC"
                        },
                        {
                            question: "Which type of biomedical signal is used to measure the electrical activity of tissues and organs?",
                            optionA: "Bioacoustic Signals",
                            optionB: "Biomechanical Signals",
                            optionC: "Bioelectric Signals",
                            optionD: "Biomagnetic Signals",
                            correctOption: "optionC"
                        },
                        {
                            question: "What is one of the primary uses of descriptive analytics in healthcare?",
                            optionA: "Predicting future disease outbreaks",
                            optionB: "Summarizing historical healthcare data",
                            optionC: "Recommending personalized treatment plans",
                            optionD: "Identifying suspicious claims",
                            correctOption: "optionB"
                        },
                        {
                            question: "What does lack of skilled workforce in healthcare data analysis primarily affect?",
                            optionA: "Data storage costs",
                            optionB: "Data privacy regulations",
                            optionC: "Drawing meaningful conclusions from data",
                            optionD: "Integration of data sources",
                            correctOption: "optionC"
                        },
                   
        
            
        
            {
                        question: "Which of the following biomedical signals is related to the mechanical properties of biological tissues?",
                        optionA: "Biomechanical Signals",
                        optionB: "Bioelectric Signals",
                        optionC: "Bioacoustic Signals",
                        optionD: "Biomagnetic Signals",
                        correctOption: "optionA"
                    }
        
        ]
        
        
        let shuffledQuestions = [] //empty array to hold shuffled selected questions
        
        function handleQuestions() { 
            //function to shuffle and push 10 questions to shuffledQuestions array
            while (shuffledQuestions.length <= 9) {
                const random = questions[Math.floor(Math.random() * questions.length)]
                if (!shuffledQuestions.includes(random)) {
                    shuffledQuestions.push(random)
                }
            }
        }
        
        
        let questionNumber = 1
        let playerScore = 0  
        let wrongAttempt = 0 
        let indexNumber = 0
        
        // function for displaying next question in the array to dom
        function NextQuestion(index) {
            handleQuestions()
            const currentQuestion = shuffledQuestions[index]
            document.getElementById("question-number").innerHTML = questionNumber
            document.getElementById("player-score").innerHTML = playerScore
            document.getElementById("display-question").innerHTML = currentQuestion.question;
            document.getElementById("option-one-label").innerHTML = currentQuestion.optionA;
            document.getElementById("option-two-label").innerHTML = currentQuestion.optionB;
            document.getElementById("option-three-label").innerHTML = currentQuestion.optionC;
            document.getElementById("option-four-label").innerHTML = currentQuestion.optionD;
        
        }
        
        
        function checkForAnswer() {
            const currentQuestion = shuffledQuestions[indexNumber] //gets current Question 
            const currentQuestionAnswer = currentQuestion.correctOption //gets current Question's answer
            const options = document.getElementsByName("option"); //gets all elements in dom with name of 'option' (in this the radio inputs)
            let correctOption = null
        
            options.forEach((option) => {
                if (option.value === currentQuestionAnswer) {
                    //get's correct's radio input with correct answer
                    correctOption = option.labels[0].id
                }
            })
           
            //checking to make sure a radio input has been checked or an option being chosen
            if (options[0].checked === false && options[1].checked === false && options[2].checked === false && options[3].checked == false) {
                document.getElementById('option-modal').style.display = "flex"
            }
        
            //checking if checked radio button is same as answer
            options.forEach((option) => {
                if (option.checked === true && option.value === currentQuestionAnswer) {
                    document.getElementById(correctOption).style.backgroundColor = "green"
                    playerScore++
                    indexNumber++
                    //set to delay question number till when next question loads
                    setTimeout(() => {
                        questionNumber++
                    }, 1000)
                }
        
                else if (option.checked && option.value !== currentQuestionAnswer) {
                    const wrongLabelId = option.labels[0].id
                    document.getElementById(wrongLabelId).style.backgroundColor = "red"
                    document.getElementById(correctOption).style.backgroundColor = "green"
                    wrongAttempt++
                    indexNumber++
                    //set to delay question number till when next question loads
                    setTimeout(() => {
                        questionNumber++
                    }, 1000)
                }
            })
        }
        
        
        
        //called when the next button is called
        function handleNextQuestion() {
            checkForAnswer()
            unCheckRadioButtons()
            //delays next question displaying for a second
            setTimeout(() => {
                if (indexNumber <= 9) {
                    NextQuestion(indexNumber)
                }
                else {
                    handleEndGame()
                }
                resetOptionBackground()
            }, 1000);
        }
        
        //sets options background back to null after display the right/wrong colors
        function resetOptionBackground() {
            const options = document.getElementsByName("option");
            options.forEach((option) => {
                document.getElementById(option.labels[0].id).style.backgroundColor = ""
            })
        }
        
        // unchecking all radio buttons for next question(can be done with map or foreach loop also)
        function unCheckRadioButtons() {
            const options = document.getElementsByName("option");
            for (let i = 0; i < options.length; i++) {
                options[i].checked = false;
            }
        }
        
        // function for when all questions being answered
        function handleEndGame() {
            let remark = null
            let remarkColor = null
        
            // condition check for player remark and remark color
            if (playerScore <= 3) {
                remark = "Bad Grades, Keep Practicing."
                remarkColor = "red"
            }
            else if (playerScore >= 4 && playerScore < 7) {
                remark = "Average Grades, You can do better."
                remarkColor = "orange"
            }
            else if (playerScore >= 7) {
                remark = "Excellent, Keep the good work going."
                remarkColor = "green"
            }
            const playerGrade = (playerScore / 10) * 100
        
            //data to display to score board
            document.getElementById('remarks').innerHTML = remark
            document.getElementById('remarks').style.color = remarkColor
            document.getElementById('grade-percentage').innerHTML = playerGrade
            document.getElementById('wrong-answers').innerHTML = wrongAttempt
            document.getElementById('right-answers').innerHTML = playerScore
            document.getElementById('score-modal').style.display = "flex"
        
        }
        
        //closes score modal and resets game
        function closeScoreModal() {
            questionNumber = 1
            playerScore = 0
            wrongAttempt = 0
            indexNumber = 0
            shuffledQuestions = []
            NextQuestion(indexNumber)
            document.getElementById('score-modal').style.display = "none"
        }
        
        //function to close warning modal
        function closeOptionModal() {
            document.getElementById('option-modal').style.display = "none"
        }